

# CONTACT

- +358 405613465
- ✓ elias@brainflight.fi
- Otakuja 3 D 45, 02150 Espoo
- www.brainflight.fi

## **EDUCATION**

2008 - 2013 TAMPERE UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY

 Master of Science (MSc), Industrial Engineering & Management

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Azure Solutions Architect
- Azure Data Engineer
- Azure Data Scientist
- Terraform Associate

### **SKILLS**

- Cloud Architecture & Engineering (Azure, AWS)
- Data Engineering (Python, SQL, Databricks)
- Machine Learning Engineering
- Full-stack Web Development (Typescript, Next.js)
- Project Management

# LANGUAGES

- Finnish (Native)
- English (Fluent)
- Swedish (Proficient)
- French (Basics)

# **ELIAS VAKKURI**

# HANDS-ON ARCHITECT WITH A BUSINESS MINDSET

## **PROFILE**

I design and build solutions in the intersection of cloud and data. I've been working with digital strategy and solutions since 2014, and implementing data platforms in multiple industries and various public clouds since 2017.

With roots in both strategy consulting and tech, my biggest strength is versatility - I'm comfortable both designing new initiatives with business representatives and implementing them with developers.

I'm most interested in projects with systemic impact, e.g. in education, energy, and healthcare.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Brainflight Oy**

2021 - PRESENT

Freelance Software Developer

Freelance software developer through my company Brainflight. See more information at www.brainflight.fi

### **Bigdatapump / CGI Advanced Analytics**

2017 - 2021

Cloud & data architect

Examples of projects:

- Designing and building Azure AI platform from scratch for public education sector
- Migration of container-based microservices to Kubernetes in public transport sector
- Data and API strategy in banking sector
- Multiple other data platform projects (data pipelines, data warehousing, DataOps)

### Magenta Advisory / BearingPoint

2014 - 2017

Senior consultant

Examples of projects:

- Product strategy definition and eCommerce acceleration in banking industry
- Long-term assignment as Agile product owner in eCommerce for an international telecom company
- Multi-year business cases for digital roadmaps in telecom sector
- · Customer data strategy for clients in media and telecom sectors